Patricio Petraglia

Munich, Germany | Linkedin: Patricio-petraglia | patriciopetraglia@gmail.com

Profile

Software developer with over five years of experience in applications development for diverse sectors. Versatile and adaptable to different technologies with provable record of success across different renown companies.

Goals oriented and problem-solving mentality with demonstrated ability to provide effective solutions for innovative software functionalities, fixes and tests.

Great team-working skills and committed.

Education

Machine Learning - Certificate of advanced study (1 year)

ITBA / Buenos Aires, Argentina / Feb. 2021 - Feb. 2022

Computer programming - Associate degree

UCES / Buenos Aires, Argentina / Aug. 2018 – Aug. 2020

GPA: 2.4 (German grading)

Mechanical engineering - 4 years completed, unfinished

ITBA / Buenos Aires, Argentina / Mar. 2009 – Mar. 2015

Certifications

Data structures and algorithms - Online specialization (9 months)

Univ. California San Diego / Coursera - online / Nov. 2023 – Present.

Grade: 100%. Credential Ids: F9CV8KP3WHP8, VQLXFHM8ASNC, DYUTVKUACX28, TLVJMAFB2Q8Z.

Work Experience

Java Developer:

San Blas / Buenos Aires, Argentina / July 2024 - Present

- Web application development in JAVA for a diversified crane company. Java Spring boot, CUBA framework, PL SQL, MySQL.
- Developing and maintaining software for business administration, recordkeeping, inventory management, sales.
- Documentation and testing.

Java Developer:

Pinteam / Munich, Germany / July 2022 – October 2023

- RCP and Eclipse plugin development in JAVA.
- Development and maintenance of automotive software products for Audi, BMW, Mercedes Benz. AUTOSAR framework.
- VRTE application feature development, bug fixes and tests. Working for Bosch.

Java Front-end Developer:

Lemondata / Buenos Aires, Argentina / April 2021 – March 2022

- API Rest development and debugging with Java.
- Taxes management and query software development for Buenos Aires city government. Java, JSF, HTML, Richfaces, Javascript, Spring, Hibernate.
- R&D projects: Intracompany tasks scheduling and management software. Java, JSF, Primefaces, HTML, Spring, Hibernate.

Software Developer - Intern:

U.S. Embassy Information Resource Management Dept. / Buenos Aires, Argentina / February 2020 – August 2020

- Web maintenance and development with MS Sharepoint.
- Workflow design and programming on C#.
- App development (widgets for MS Sharepoint).
- I.T. support, troubleshooting, accounts and permissions management.

Back-end Developer:

GA, globant associate - Equifax / Buenos Aires, Argentina / April 2017 - August 2019

- Platform engine migration from Java to Python.
- Financial decision models programming on Python.
- Testing and documentation writing.

Skills

Languages:

```
English - Advanced. Certifications: IELTS 8.0, CAE.
```

Spanish – Native.

Italian – Basic, Certifications: A2 Language school (CUI - Buenos Aires).

German – Basic, A2

Programming languages:

Java, Javascript, Python, C# (.NET), C++, SQL.